Let's take a closer look at our update mechanisms to see if we can improve things.
我们仔细研究下我们的更新机制 看看是否有任何改进之处
Remember where this policy update rule comes from?
还记得这个策略更新规则来自何处吗？
It is based on the policy gradients method where we
它基于策略梯度方法
change the policy parameters by a small fraction,
我们以很小的分数 α
alpha, of the gradient of the objective function, J theta.
目标函数的梯度 jθ 更改策略参数
Now, this gradient can be expressed as the expected value of
这个梯度可以表示为策略乘以某个得分函数 R
the derivative of the log probabilities produced by the policy times some score function,
生成的对数概率的导数预期值
R. In this case,
在此处
we are using the action value function Q-hat as the score function.
我们将动作值函数 q^ 作为得分函数
What makes this approach work is that we can compute this expectation
这个方法可行的原因是我们可以采取很小的步长
iteratively by taking small steps defined by our learning rate, alpha.
（由学习速率 α 定义）迭代地计算该预期值
It is important to ensure that we are always taking small steps.
务必确保始终采取很小的步长
We still want to move in the direction pointed to by the gradient,
我们依然希望沿着梯度所指的方向移动
but we want to avoid any giant leaps because we are ultimately sampling
但是需要避免很大的步长 因为最终是抽样随机流程
a stochastic process and individual samples may vary a lot.
单个样本可能会变化很大
Wherever there is an expected value,
只要是预期值
there is an associated variance.
就存在相关的方差
And if we're trying to estimate this expected value,
如果我们尝试估算这个预期值
it would be nice to have low variance among the samples,
则最好样本之间的方差很小
that would make the process more stable.
这样使得该流程更加稳定
The magnitude of this variance is mainly affected by the score function here, Q-hat.
该方程的大小主要受到得分函数 q^ 的影响
At each time step,
在每个时间步
the value of Q-hat can vary quite a bit since it is based on individual rewards.
q^ 的值可能变化很大 因为它基于单个奖励
This can result in policy update steps of different sizes,
这样可能会导致策略更新步长不一
a small step here,
有时候是很小的步长
a giant leap there.
有时候是很大的步长
Okay, so how can we reduce this variance?
如何减小这一方差？
Let's think of Q values as being sampled from some distribution.
假设 q 值抽样自某个分布
Now, let's say this fits a normal or Gaussian distribution.
假设这个分布是正态分布或高斯分布
Can you tell what the mean of this distribution is?
能算出该分布的均值是什么吗？
Well, the mean is the expected value of Q-hat.
均值是 q^ 的预期值
For a particular state, S,
对于特定的状态 s
this distribution is over the space of actions.
这个分布针对的是动作空间
So, the expected value is essentially equal to the value of the state.
因此预期值本质上等于状态值
If we subtract this mean from each Q value and use that as our new score function,
如果用每个 Q 值减去这个均值并用作新的得分函数
that should bring the mean score value down to
这样会使得均值得分值降低为 0
zero and help reduce the variance of update steps.
有助于减小更新步长的偏差
This new score function is known as the Advantage Function.
这个新得分函数称之为优势函数
Intuitively, it makes a lot of sense.
可以直观地看出它很合理
A Q value tells us how much reward we expect to
Q 值告诉我们在状态 s 采取动作 a
get by taking action A and state S. Whereas,
预期可以获得的奖励
the advantage value tells us how much more reward
优势函数告诉我们在状态的预期值之外
we expect beyond the expected value of the state.
我们预期会获得多少额外的奖励
That is, what are we gaining by taking this action instead of any action at random?
即我们采取该动作（而不是任何随机的动作）会获得什么
So, not only does the Advantage Function stabilize learning,
优势函数不仅会稳定学习过程
it also provides a better way to differentiate between actions.
而且可以更好地区分动作